Nike has been making a whole lot of
noise lately with their new line of
strength gear so of course I had no
choice but to snag a pair of dumbbells
to review for you guys I have the 50 lb
pair these are going to range from 5 to
100 lb they feature rubber coated hex
heads and the handle design is going to
change as you go up and wait there's a
lot of hype surrounding this gear so
let's get right into
this
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video we're going to be breaking down
Nike's brand new dumbbells if you're new
to the channel don't know how this whole
process works in this video today I'm
going to tell you everything there is to
know about these dumbbells from the
price to some pros and cons and then of
course who should or maybe should not
purchase them but before I do that I got
to make sure yall know that we've
reviewed a ton of dumbbells on barb.
comom and we came up with our own best
list so if you want to check that out
all you got to do is search barbend best
dumbbells it's going to pull right up
for you you can find out for yourself
which ones we like the
best all right so once again these
dumbbells from Nike are going to range
from 5 lb to 100 lb now I'm sure some
people might need more than 100 but
honestly that's a really solid range for
the majority of home gym owners so you
can definitely find some that work well
with you I really like the fact that
these are hex dumbbells hex dumbbells
are Elite in my opinion you know
especially compared to a rounded head
because they're going to be great for
any floor work like burpees push-ups
anything like that I also think you know
this Contour design right here on you
know the edges just provides an elite
aesthetic overall and then also you know
these are in fact rubber coated so it's
going to protect the dumbbell your floor
and any surrounding equipment you know
especially you drop them they're not
going to roll too far they're still
going to roll a little bit but not that
bad the steel handles here are in fact
Chrome plated so you're going to get a
decent amount of rust and corrosion
resistance but for me personally I'm not
too crazy about ergonomically shaped
handles yes as you go up and wait there
are going to be they are going to have a
straight handle but you know not
everybody is lifting with 70 plus pounds
of weight and not everybody cares about
an ergonomically shaped handle and then
plus you know I just prefer a handle
that's fully knurled and these aren't so
it's really just some personal
preference right there now these can get
pretty pricey okay they're not sold as a
full set and they're not even sold in
pairs so for example one 50 lb dumbbell
right here is going to cost you right
around 95 bucks so it could just get
pretty pricey overall and then another
thing here is that there's a plus minus
3% weight accuracy with these dumbbells
now it's not a rarity you know across
the rest of the market we're going to
weigh these in a minute and you honestly
might be surprised by how much they
actually
[Music]
weigh so once again Nike does not off
offer these dumbbells in a full set or
as actual pairs so this 50 lb pair right
here is going to cost you about 250
bucks after shipping and taxes it's
about average overall compared to the
rest of the market now with rep Fitness
you know they don't charge for shipping
so 50lb pair from them it's about $214
now if you go for rogue that's going to
cost you about 265 bucks so it's not
terrible one thing that Nike does do
though is the more weight you have in
your cart you're going to get you know a
good chunk of a discount on your
shipping so definitely you know be aware
of that as you go to make a purchase
however you know at the end of the day
if you're looking for the best bank for
your buck purchase with dumbbells I
would suggest going after an adjustable
dumbbell system and we actually have a
best list video detailing our top picks
so definitely go and check that out as
[Music]
well all right so remember these R hex
dumbbells Elite in my opinion you know
they're going to allow you to do floor
work like push-ups and burpees and stuff
like like that I don't want to do
burpees with these 5050 Pounders but you
know that hex design definitely comes in
handy especially if you drop them you
know it's going to prevent a whole lot
of rolling and that's definitely
something that you want and then this
rubber right here obviously protects the
actual Integrity of the dumbbell as well
as you know prevent damage to your
flooring and then any surrounding
equipment which is really nice this
Contour design it's pretty unique you
know with most hex dumbells they have a
a sharp I guess angle right there
nothing bad about the other con or
anything like that I just think this
looks really good overall now you do
have a steel handle right here with this
chrome plating so it's going to offer a
pretty solid amount of resistance to
rust and corrosion which is definitely
something that you want now I'm not
crazy about ergonomically shaped handles
if you don't know what that is so the
middle part right here is thicker than
anywhere
else it's personal preference right as
you go up and weight there once you get
to 70 lbs it'll be straight across but
this knurling pattern doesn't change I'm
also not crazy about this style of
nerling pattern you know Rogue a lot of
other companies do this I prefer you
know a fully knurled handle that way
wherever you grab you're getting the
same grip no matter
what okay I got my scale right here
let's weigh these out and just see
exactly what we're working with all
right so let me turn my scale back on it
to shut off on
me all right cool here we go remember
this is 50 lbs supposed to
be that is
53 17 six kind of messing around right
there so if it was less than you know 50
lbs I think that would be something to
you know be you know alarming I guess 53
you know being heavier it's okay it's
not ideal let's see if this other one is
the exact
same it's almost a full pound
lighter 52.1 three that's less than
ideal you
know I'm not crazy about that at all
um that's surprising you know remember I
said earlier plusus 3% weight accuracy
it's not completely rare across the
fitness industry but the fact that these
aren't even the same like I said it's
just a bit alarming to me I think these
are great for anybody who wants some
easily obtainable dumbbells to add to
their home gym you can walk into your
local Dick Sporting Goods and they're
basically just going to be sitting there
waiting for you plus if you have a
preference for an ergonomically shaped
handle I think you'll enjoy the fact
that these are ergonomically shaped from
5 to 65 lbs however they are pretty
pricey you know especially as you buy a
bunch of them you know despite the free
shipping as you go up and weight and the
weight and accuracy is definitely going
to be a problem for a lot of you so
definitely keep that in mind
[Music]
too that's all I got for y'all today on
the Nike dumbbells these look great on
paper I think they have an elite
aesthetic and they're super easy to get
your hands on but they are a little bit
pricey and then the you know the weight
and accuracy is a bit of an issue for me
thanks for hanging out with me y'all I
hope this video was helpful and I was
able to tell you everything there is to
know about these dumbbells as always
keep your eyes peeled for my next video
but for now head over to barb. comom cuz
we have a full written article about
these dumbbells that I think you should
check out all you got to do is search
barbend Nike dumbbell review article is
going to pull right up for you you can
go over every sing thing we talked about
here today I'll catch youall next
[Music]
time